Sasuke's Story: The Last One
(サスケ)その力で→
You were gonna use that to
get revenge against the Uchiha
血之池一族を地獄谷に追いやった
うちはに対する→
who forced the Chinoike Clan
to Hell Valley?
復讐を企てたわけか。
狙いは最初から 俺だったんだな。
So I was your target
from the very start.
(チノ)
起爆人間に木ノ葉を襲わせれば→
If I sent Exploding Humans
to Hidden Leaf Village,
あんたは きっと戻ってくる。
you were sure to return.
あんたを木ノ葉の里ごと→
I planned to kill you and
the entire Leaf Village, but…
亡き者に
するつもりだったんだけど。
竹ノ村で 俺に出会ってしまった。
You happened to meet me
at Bamboo Village, is that it?
怖いよね 偶然って。
Coincidence is a scary thing,
don't you think?
あの村は 以前のお返しに
襲っただけだったんだけど→
We attacked that village just to
get back at them for the last time…
まさか近くに→
Meeting you there was
the last thing we expected.
うちはサスケ あんたがいたなんて。
でも 竹ノ村の村長が→
But thanks to
the head of the Bamboo Village's
interesting parting words,
おもしろいこと
言い残してくれたんで→
we changed our plans.
計画を変更したってわけ。
((イオウ : 許さんぞ 風心め～！))
I'll never forgive you…
Fuushin!
風心を捜す俺と同行。
I happened to be looking for Fuushin,
so you joined up with me and
ことあるごとに
起爆人間で陽動し→
used your Exploding Humans whenever
something happened as a diversion.
ノワキ いや
風心のチャクラ刀で俺を狙った。
And Nowaki, rather Fuushin, would come
after me with his chakra sword.
殺せなかったときのために→
And just in case
you couldn't kill me,
かつての仲間に
風心を装わせる保険までかけて。
you went so far as
to ask an old partner
to stand by and
pretend to be Fuushin.
どう？ 私を殺す？
So what now?
Are you gonna kill me?
お互い 血之池とうちはの
最後の一人同士→
You and me… We're the last ones from
the Chinoike and Uchiha Clans.
一族の生き残りをかけて→
Let's put it all on the line
殺し合おうよ。
and fight to the death!
あいにくだが
そんなことに興味はない。
Unfortunately,
I'm not interested in that.
フン 相変わらずだね。
You're the same as usual…
だけど
いつまでも そんな涼しい顔で→
But don't think
you can go around
with that aloof expression
on your face forever.
いられるとは思わないことさ。
血之池一族は 血を使うことで
さまざまな術を扱う。
The Chinoike Clan uses blood
to handle all kinds of jutsu.
そして この場所。
And here in this location…
鉄分を多く含んだ この赤池は→
this red lake with
its high iron content…
血之池の力を更に強くしてくれる。
will make the power of
the Chinoike even stronger!
なに!?
What?!
くらえ！
Take this!
くっ… いけ！
Go!
あ！
まだ続けるか？
Do you still want to continue?
傷口からチャクラを？
Chakra is entering
from my wound?!
フッ…。
なに!?
What?!
私のチャクラは傷口をふさいで→
My chakra seals the wound
and waits.
そのときを待つの。
そのとき？
Waits for what?
決まってるでしょ。
Isn't it obvious?
うっ… ガハッ…。
さよなら うちはサスケ。
Good bye, Sasuke Uchiha.
そうやって
起爆人間を作っていたのか。
So that's how you made
the Exploding Humans?
写輪眼!? あっ…。
The Sharingan?!
私は あんたが
うらやましかったよ サスケ。
I envied you, Sasuke.
You were born in
the Hidden Leaf Village
木ノ葉という里に生まれ
うちはという名を持ち→
and bore the Uchiha name…
愛してくれる家族がいて。
and you had a family
that loved you.
里を抜けたあとは
悪名をとどろかせていたけど→
When you deserted your village,
you and your reputation were notorious.
今は自由に旅をしている。
But even now,
you're allowed to travel freely.
それは あんたを愛し
守ってくれる人がいるからだ。
That's because you have people
who love and protect you.
I know…
(チノ)わかるよ。
You've always, always had someone
who kept loving you, no matter what.
あんたは ずっと ずっと ずっと→
誰かに愛され続けて
生きてきたんだろうって。
独りきりだった私とは 違う！
You're not like me…
I've been alone from the beginning!
You've been alone
from the beginning!
((俺の何がわかるってんだよ。
How the hell do you think
you understand?
はじめから
独りきりだったてめえに→
俺の何がわかるってんだ！
It's because I have these ties,
that I feel this agony.
つながりがあるからこそ
苦しいんだ。
How could you
possibly understand
それを失うことが どんなもんか→
what it feels like to lose all that?!
(お前なんかに
わかってたまるか！))
だからって…。
So…
だからって
どうして木ノ葉のために戦うの？
So why do you fight for
the Hidden Leaf?!
木ノ葉の葉は鮮やかで 根は暗い！
The leaves of the Hidden Leaf
are brilliant,
but its roots are black!
木ノ葉には光と闇がある！
There is light and darkness
in the Hidden Leaf!
あんたの一族は
木ノ葉の養分になるために→
Your clan was used up and
absorbed by the Leaf's roots
as nourishment!
根に吸収されたんでしょ！
So why do you go so far for them?!
なのに どうして木ノ葉のために！
Because I'm alive.
俺が生きているからだ。
What do you mean?
どういう意味？
俺を救い出した友がいる。
I have a friend who saved me.
互いの心を痛み合うことができる
友がいる。
A friend with whom I can share
my pain, and him, with me.
そいつは いつか この世界も
そうなればいいと願っている。
His wish is that one day
the world will be like us.
そんな世界 絶対にありえない。
A world like that is impossible.
そんなの ただの
きれいごとじゃないか。
That's just wishful thinking!
That's why he wants to
make it real!
きれいごとだから 実現したい。
そう願う心が
俺を木ノ葉につなげている。
And it's that hopeful heart that
connects me to the Hidden Leaf!
俺の兄がそうだったように
この世界を陰から支え→
To be like my older brother…
and support this world from
the shadows, and…
そして…。
そして？
And?
この世界が見つめる先に 光を。
And look beyond this world…
to the light!
そんな世界 私は見たくない！
I don't want to see such a world!
Enough already! Kill me!
もういい 殺せ！ 早く殺せ！
Hurry and kill me!
Chino!
(風心)チノ！
風心！
Fuushin!
グッ…。
風心！
Fuushin!
風心 なんで出てきたのよ！
Fuushin?!
What are you doing here?
風心？
Fuushin?
俺が言った言葉の意味が
今ならわかるはずだ。
Now, you should be able to understand
the meaning of my words.
((俺を救い出した友がいる。
I have a friend who saved me.
(互いの心を痛み合うことができる
友がいる))
A friend with whom I can share
my pain, and him, with me.
If you're going to kill someone,
kill me.
殺すなら 俺だけにしろ。
Fuushin, it's okay.
風心 もういい。
もういいよ。
It's okay.
あんたが死んだら 私が痛い。
I'd be in pain…if you died.
チノ。
Chino…
Sasuke dear, I wish I didn't meet you
at Bamboo Village.
竹ノ村で サスケちゃんに
会わなきゃよかったよ。
そうすれば
一方的に憎んでいられたのにさ。
Then I could have kept
on hating you.
それに
あんたが言うきれいごとの世界→
Also, I want to see
this world that you speak of…
私も見てみたいや。
(ヒナタ)これが最後。
This is the last one…
上腕動脈に到達。
It's penetrated the brachial artery.
(ヒナタ)大丈夫。 もう この人の中に
特殊なチャクラは流れていない。
We're good now.
There's no more unusual chakra
flowing inside of him now.
(サクラ)ありがとう。
Thank you.
(サクラ)ヒナタが協力してくれた
おかげで助かったわ。
What would I have done
without you?
サクラちゃんの
高い技術があってこそだよ。
I think it's all because of
your exceptional skill, Sakura!
昨晩 首謀者の身柄が
送検されてきたんだよね？
The ringleader was turned over to
the authorities last night, right?
Yes.
うん。
サスケ君も一緒に？
Was Sasuke there?
そう思ってたんだけど→
I thought he would be.
木ノ葉の忍が 湯の国まで
引き取りに行ったんだって。
But they asked the Leaf shinobi go over
to the Land of Steam to take custody.
身柄を拘束した本人は戻ってこず。
The one who captured
the ringleader didn't return…
はぁ…。
(カカシ)どうも。
Hello.
私が首謀者だよ。
I'm the perpetrator.
すべて 私が責任をとる。
I take all responsibility.
だから 他のやつらは
穏便に済ませてやってほしい。
So please go easy on the other two.
チノ！ 俺たちは
そんなこと 望んじゃいない。
Chino, that's not what we want.
(カリュウ)そ… そうです チノさん！
俺は…。
That's right, Miss Chino!
I–!
まぁ 落ち着いて。
Now calm down…
実は 霧隠れの水影が キミたちを
引き取りたいそうなんだよ。
Actually, the Mizukage of
the Land of Mist
wants to take custody of you.
ど… どうして？
W-Why?
負の連鎖を止めるのは
今しかないってことね。
Now's the only time to stop
the chain of negativity.
どうぞ。
Please come in.
(メイ)挨拶は抜きよ。
Let's skip the greetings.
(メイ)あなたたちと
昔の霧隠れの因縁は→
I'd once heard about your past connection
to the Hidden Mist.
聞いたことがあったの。
えっ？
Huh?
If it's okay with you…
あなたたちが
よければって話だけど→
霧隠れのために尽力してほしい。
I'd like you to help
the Hidden Mist.
な… なんで？
W-Why?
キミたちのやったことは→
You must atone for what you did
for the rest of your lives.
一生をかけて
償わなきゃならないものだ。
だけど それは すべての忍が→
But every shinobi, great and small,
must bear the same burden.
大なり小なり
抱えているものでもある。
俺もそうだよ。
I'm no different.
もう一度 戦ってみないか？
自分の人生と。
Would you like to fight again…
with your own life?
And, there's another thing
I need to let you know.
それと １つ 伝えておかなきゃ
ならないことがあってね。
今ごろ あいつが…。
Around now, he's…
(エン)フン…。
な… なんと なんと！
W-What is this…!
[マイク]最後のうちはこと うちはサスケが
コロシアムに帰ってきた！
The last Uchiha...
a.k.a. Sasuke Uchiha has
returned to the Coliseum!
To a victim,
((被害者にしてみれば
加害者も第三者も一緒。
the assailant and a third party
are no different.
ここで行われている金持ちどもの
道楽を止めることなく→
People are no better than
the assailant
if they didn't try to help.
同情的な言葉を
口にするだけのサスケちゃんだって→
If you only pity the loser
and do nothing
to stop the decadence of the rich…
you're just as guilty, Sasuke.
(共犯者にすぎないよ))
俺は すべての挑戦を受ける。
I will welcome all challenges!
And I will free all shinobi!
そして すべての忍を解放する。
うちはの目が欲しければ
かかってこい！
If you desire the Uchiha's eye,
come and get it!
サスケちゃんが!?
Sasuke is—?!
でも あそこには
血継限界が大勢いる！
But there are many shinobi
with Kekkei Genkai there!
Even someone like Sasuke…
いくら サスケちゃんでも…。
(ナルト)サスケをなめるなってばよ。
Don't underestimate Sasuke,
ya know!
サスケは たぶん
お前のためにやってんだ。
Sasuke's probably doing this
for your sake.
So he will never, ever lose!
だから 絶対 負けねえ。
お前が サスケの…。
So you're Sasuke's?
ん？ あぁ
友達の うずまきナルトだってばよ。
Yeah, I'm his friend.
I'm Naruto Uzumaki.
ハハッ！
Your friend saved me.
お前の友が私を救い出してくれた。
感謝している。
I'm very grateful.
そっか。
I see!
ハァ ハァ ハァ…。
[マイク]ま… まさか まさかの展開だ！
Th-This is something
no one's ever imagined!
Sasuke Uchiha has beaten
each and every shinobi!
[マイク]うちはサスケ すべての忍に勝利！
Which means, he has acquired
every, single shinobi!
[マイク]イコール すべての忍を
手に入れたということだ！
(フツ)俺たちは どうなるんだ？
What's gonna happen to us?
雲隠れに引き取ってもらう。
The Hidden Cloud will take you in.
The Hidden Cloud?
雲隠れ？
(エー)いかにも！
Indeed!
(エー)すべての忍は
我が雲隠れが保護する。
We, the Hidden Cloud, will
safeguard all shinobi!
同時に ここで
違法な賭博に手を染めていた→
At the same time, everyone who took part
in the illegal gambling here
お前たちの身柄も拘束する。
will be taken into custody.
(ダルイ)あぁ だるい…。
This is so dull.
(エン)やばいでしょう！
This isn't looking good.
来てやったぞ 小僧。
I'm here, kid.
感謝する。
I'm grateful.
Be grateful to your Lord Sixth.
感謝なら六代目にすることだ。
あいつが この島には
どの里よりも→
– He came and insisted...
– Hurry and come here!
that this island
was close to my village,
わしらの里が近い
これは雲隠れの仕事だ。
and that it was the Cloud's business
to deal with it.
そう言うから来てやったまで。
だるい。
That's why we're here…
So dull…
昔 ナルトが→
Long ago,
Naruto put his hands together
and passionately argued for you.
お前のために両手をついて
熱弁したことがあった。
弟のビーを拉致したお前を→
OFFICIAL MISSIVE TO
THE LORD HOKAGE
FROM THE RAIKAGE
It was the time you kidnapped
my kid brother, Bee,
and Danzo agreed to our request
わしらの依頼でダンゾウが
抜け忍として→
to mark you a Rogue Ninja
and assassinate you.
始末することを
許可したときだ。
((サスケを うちはサスケを
始末するのを→
I want you to cancel
the disposal of Sasuke Uchiha!
やめてもらいてえんだ
お願いだってばよ！
I'm begging you!
I don't want us killing each other
for revenge anymore!
(もう復讐で殺しあうようなこと
したくねえんだ！))
I'm glad we didn't kill you
back then.
お前を始末しなくてよかった。
己を知り 人を知り→
Know yourself and know others,
and never alter your path again.
二度と道を違えるな。
Feel the significance of why
you can walk this world freely.
お前が 今 自由にこの世界を
歩いている意味を感じろ。
そして
周りを納得させる理由も作れ。
And create a reason to
convince others around you.
Perhaps with this incident,
you just created one.
今回の件で
１つ作れたかもしれんな。
だが １つじゃ足りんぞ。
But just one won't be enough.
(大蛇丸)あなたは
捕まらなかったの？
You weren't caught?
ご覧のとおり。
I'm here, aren't I?
(大蛇丸)
計画どおりになったのかしら？
Did things work out as planned?
おかげさまで。
Thanks to you, it did.
狭いコミュニティーでは
争いごとが生まれやすい。
Conflict breaks out easily
in small communities.
長年 共に肩を寄せ合い
生きてきたというのに→
Even though they've lived shoulder
to shoulder for many years,
小さないざこざが積もり重なり
憎しみ合って→
even the smallest incident
festers hatred
and in the end, they end up
killing each other off.
最後は同士討ちだ。
まるで うちは一族のことみたい。
That sounds like the Uchiha Clan.
確かに似ているけども これは→
They were definitely like that, however…
血之池一族の真実です。
This is the truth of
the Chinoike Clan.
妻が巻き込まれて死んだ時点で→
When my wife got wrapped up
in everything and died…
いろんなことが どうでも
よくなってしまいましたよ。
lots of things didn't matter anymore.
That's why you killed
your entire clan?
だから一族を皆殺しにした？
それでも 娘は
案外 かわいいもんだ。
Even still, my daughter
is quite endearing.
And you saw with your own eyes
the foolish thing
そのかわいい娘が
バカなマネをしているのを→
that your dear daughter of yours
was doing in the Coliseum.
コロシアムで直に見た。
I wonder if that's why
you gave up on acquiring Sasuke,
だから サスケ君を
手に入れることを諦め→
and used him instead
to stop your daughter?
彼を使って
娘を止めたってとこかしら。
親バカね。
You're such a doting parent…
I consider myself more
of a foolish parent…
どっちかっていうと
バカ親ですけどね。
それにしても
不思議な感じだってばよ。
Still it feels strange.
Sasuke's not back in the village,
yet he's protecting it.
サスケは里にいねえのに
里のことを守ってんだもんな。
そうね サスケ君みたいに
優秀な忍じゃないと→
You're right.
There are so many things
we can't do
できないことは たくさんあるし。
without a skilled shinobi like Sasuke.
There are guys who do
terrible things like this time,
今回みたいに
とんでもねえことを→
しでかしちまうやつも
いるけどよ。
but I guess everything works out
ちゃんとできる
サスケみたいなやつが→
しっかり対応していけば
いいんだよな。
as long as there are guys
like Sasuke to counter it.
うん？ サクラちゃん
なんか嬉しそうだってばよ。
You seem kinda happy, Sakura.
Huh?
え？
フフ。
サスケ君 言ってたんだ
旅に出る前。
Sasuke said to me before
he left on his journey…
((罪を償う旅でもある))
This is a trip to atone for my sins.
今回の件で サスケ君が→
With this recent incident,
I know that Sasuke is
definitely making inroads.
確かな足取りで
前に進んでるのがわかったから。
ただ。
うん？
Just…
I just wish I was there next to him…
その隣に
自分が並べていないことが…。
F-Forget what I just said!
い 今言ったこと 忘れなさい！
Huh?
え？ グハッ！
カカシからか。
It's probably from Kakashi.
汚い… ナルトの字だな。
So messy. It's Naruto's writing…
Sasuke…
「サスケ お前ってば 里にいねえのに
ちゃんと里のことを守ってる。
You're not back in the village,
but you're still protecting it.
まるで警務部隊みてえだな」。
You're just like the Leaf Police Force!
HIDDEN LEAF POLICE FORCE
Are you going to join too?
((兄さんも ここに入るの？
(イタチ)さあ どうかなあ？
HIDDEN LEAF POLICE FORCE
Well… I wonder about that...
Why not?
そうしなよ
大きくなったら→
When I grow up, I'm going to join
the Leaf Police Force too!
(俺も警務部隊に
入るからさ！))
久しぶりに 帰るか。
It's been a while…
Maybe I'll go home.
Regarding the issue with
the Land of Silence,
it's going to become violent, eventually…
If they find out we've independently
started investigating,
it's going to get troublesome.
That being said, it would be b